Summer Lee (Nicklas Lee Woodman)



📍 Halifax, Nova Scotia | 📧 <u>hello@summerlee.design</u> | 🙆 <u>summerlee.design</u> | 🤝 <u>Connect on LinkedIn</u>





Product Designer, UI Systems & UX Research

Five years of agency experience in a startup environment, communicating data-informed design decisions cross-functionally with designers, developers, clients, and managers. Specializing in UX research, accessible UI design systems, wireframing, prototyping, and visual design for mobile, desktop, and wearable tech.

Education

(2018-2021) NOVA SCOTIA COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Diploma - Business Administration

(2017-2018) SOBEY SCHOOL OF BUSINESS AT SMU

Foundational - Business/Commerce

(2012-2014) CENTRE FOR ARTS AND TECHNOLOGY

Advanced Diploma - Graphic Design & Web Development

Certificates

(2017) UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA - REMOTE

Software Product Management

(2016) UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO - REMOTE

Building iOS Applications

(2015) UCI - REMOTE

Project Management Practices & Principles

Professional Skills

FLUENT

- UX Research
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Visual Design
- Usability Testing
- Analytical Reporting
- iOS Human Interface Guidelines & Material Design

FAMILIAR

- UI Design Systems
- Lean Design & Agile Scrum
- Service Design
- WCAG Accessibility
- French (Canadian)

Software Applications

FLUENT

- Figma, Sketch & InVision
- Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop
- Slack, Zoom, & Trello
- Microsoft 365 & Google Workplace
- Git, GitHub, & SourceTree

FAMILIAR

- Jira & Confluence
- Framer & WebFlow
- Google Analytics
- Amplitude & MixPanel
- Meta Business Suite
- HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript
- React Native & Bootstrap
- Xcode & Android Studio

Experience

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER, MINDSEA DEVELOPMENT

HALIFAX, NS, FULL-TIME PERMANENT – APR 2021 - MAY 2023 (2 YEARS 2 MONTHS)

- Leading the product design of a health tech app from MVP to v1.8, while scaling the design to support a total membership of ~80,000 active users.
- Facilitating usability testing sessions and user research interviews, using data and insights to reduce customer support times from 72 to 24 hours.
- Designing UI wireframes and UX documents for marketing and development teams, leading to a 4.9/5 star rating over 1000+ reviews across Google Play/Apple App Stores.
- Reviewing front-end React Native UI components with developers to meet WCAG AA standards before submitting builds to Google Console & App Store Connect.
- Documenting and teaching internal design standards, app store guidelines, and internal sales processes to 4 junior-mid design team members.

COMMUNICATIONS DESIGNER, LAKECITY WORKS (NON-PROFIT)

DARTMOUTH, NS, INTERNSHIP - MAY 2019 - AUG 2019 (4 MONTHS)

- Designing sales materials/marketing collateral that meet Québec bilingual standards.
- Managing a 12-week social media campaign with a \$5,000 seasonal advertising budget.

MARKETING DESIGNER, CANOPY CREATIVE

WOLFVILLE, NS, FREELANCE - MAY 2018 - DEC 2018 (8 MONTHS)

Consulting across 10 Atlantic Canadian organizations with a team of 6 digital marketers.

WEB DESIGNER, BREWERSINSIGHT

HALIFAX, NS, FREELANCE – JAN 2018 - APR 2018 (4 MONTHS)

- Prototyping 3 web apps using frameworks such as Bootstrap with a team of 6 Dalhousie research students, developers, and hardware/firmware engineers.
- Partnering with CEO and COO to implement predictive analysis algorithms that detect key metrics for craft brewery equipment into web app prototypes.

TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGEMENT, CODE+MORTAR

HALIFAX, NS, INTERNSHIP - MAY 2017 - AUG 2017 (4 MONTHS)

- Managing a team of 8 full stack web developers and creative designers with a Director.
- Coordinating concurrent requirements for 10 WordPress websites and Vue.js web apps.

MOBILE UI/UX MOBILE DESIGNER, MINDSEA DEVELOPMENT

HALIFAX, NS, FULL-TIME PERMANENT - MAY 2014 - DEC 2016 (2 YEARS 8 MONTHS)

• Focusing on human-centred UI design & UX research for Canadian startups, funded scaleups, and national enterprises within News Media and Digital Publishing.

PRODUCT SPECIALIST, APPLE RETAIL CANADA

HALIFAX, NS, PERMANENT FULL-TIME - SEP 2012 - MAY 2014 (1 YEAR 9 MONTHS)

- Facilitating the customer journey by discovering user needs to pair with product benefits.
- Teaching live in-person technical workshops for a dozen community members per session.